RG 074:001, Small Genealogical Collections
Connecticut State Library
Small genealogical collections
Connecticut State Library
Artificial collection of genealogical material consisting of single items or small collections less than .25 cubic feet.
RG074_001
Scope and Content
Artificial collection of genealogical material consisting of single items or small collections.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Adams family; Barney family; Beckwith family; Birdseye family; Blackman family; Brown family; Bushnell family; Catlin family; Clark family; Colt family; Cornell family; Dart family; DeHaven family; Dennis family; Denslow family; Ellsworth family; Farnham family; Francis family; Goddard family; Gordon family; Griffin family; Hall family; Hallett family; Hanks family; Hastings family; Hibbert family; Higgins family; Hinkley family; Jewett family; Johnson family; Kelly family; Lothrop family; Lyman family; MacKenzie family; Marsh family; Morrison family; Norris family; Norton family; Orcutt family; Oviatt family; Patton family; Peck family; Pember family; Rathbone family; Remington family; Robbins family; Rogers family; Russell family; Selden family; Seymour family; Skinner family; Slate family; Smith family; Stowe family; Sturges family; Thorne family; Trumnbull family; Vaughan family; Walsh family; Warner family; White family; Woodruff family
Places:
Connecticut -- Genealogy
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should request these items by Accession number.
Some of these records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Collections list by family name
- A
  - Ancestry of Rev. Edward Bradford Adams, M.A. of Pasadena, California / compiled by E. B. Adams, 1950; 1 volume; 1999-103
    Presented by compiler to the Connecticut State Library, August 31, 1950.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 Ad1708.
    Related material may be found at
  - Askue
    See: "Family lines / Mabel (Smith) Askue" listed under Smith.
- B
  - Barney genealogical notes, undated; T003193
  - Frederick H. Beckwith correspondence and notes, 1911-1953; 2002-042
    Original letters and notes to go with: Additional Beckwith notes: including Avery, Ely, Gilbert, Holmes, Lee, Smith (Nehemiah, Richard, and Simon), Southerland, Wightman, and Williams families, with miscellaneous historical data ... / by Frederick H. Beckwith
    Donated to the Connecticut State Library by Frederick H. Beckwith, Stratford, Conn. on January 14, 1957.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 B389be.
  - Outline of the Birdseye family in America / compiled by George F.H. Birdseye; edited by Lucien H. Birdseye, circa 1934; T0033217; negative photostat, 2 copies
    A copy is available at
  - Blackman/Blackmon family notes / compiled by Catherine Taggart, 1954; 2002-030
    Gift of compiler.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 B56t.
  - Brown genealogical notes, undated; T003194
  - Memoir of Col. Charles Burrall and other biographies; Coipied for John Dickinson Burrall, a lineal descendant of the sixth generation, undated; 1 volume; 2002-043
    Contents: Summary of Burrall lineage; Sketch of the life of Col. Charles Burrall written by himself when 80 years of age, from copy made 1829 by his granddaughter Mrs. Elna Rockwell Emerson, this copy made apparently by the latter's son or daughter, E.M. Emerson of Rockwood, Ill., Sept. 1861; Recollections of Col. Charles Burrall, Sr., by grandson Thomas D. Burrall (1786-1872) of Geneva, N.Y.; Some recollections of William Burrall, by his granddaughter Elisabeth B. Belden, South Canann, December 15, 1886; William Morgan Burrall (died South Canaan, November 21, 1856); William M. Burrall: Extract from lecture delivered before the Litchfield County Bar, April 13, 1870 by Charles F. Sedgewick, Esq.; Obituary of William P. Burrall, by Henry C. Robinson, in the Hartford Courant, March 4, 1784, clipping of same from newspaper; John Milton Burrall, 1834-1880 [and his son, John Dickinson Burrall, born 1880,] written by the latter's mother, Mary D[ickinson] Burrall, Richmond, Va., November 28, 1908; Extraneous material.
    Purchased from Cedric Robinson, December 15, 1955.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 B942.
  - Bushnell genealogical chart, undated; T003195
- C
  - Catlin genealogical notes and charts, undated; T003196
    Related material may be found at [CSL call number History Reference Spec.Gen.File Catlin]
  - Clark and allied families records / compiled by Grace Clark, Marblehead, Massachusetts, circa 1932; T003218; negative photostat
    Title from note on verso of title page: The genealogy of William Henry Clark.
    Related material may be found at [CSL call number History Reference Spec.Gen.File Clark]
  - Notebook containing Cornell, Hallett, Thorne family genealogical notes, undated; 1 volume; T003269
    Related material may be found at [CSL call number History Reference Spec.Gen.File Cornell]
  - Descendants of John Coult: who sailed from England and arrived in America September 4, 1633, also ancestral line from Roderick Bissel Jones and Edward Payson Jones Jr. ..., also 47 connected generations of kings, emperors. 1933, negative photostat; T003219
    Related material may be found at [CSL call number History Reference Spec.Gen.File Colt]
- D
  - Dart notes / compiled by Lucius B. Barbour, circa 1934; 1 volume; 1993-001
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 D257bar.
  - Some descendants of Jonathan Dehaven4 (Edward1 Peter2, Samuel3) son of Samuel & Susanna (Spaulding) DeHaven / compiled from the records of Edward Perrine Cody by [Samuel Gaylord Payne], circa 1953; 2002-031; 12 leaves, typescript and manuscript, annotated; negative photostat
    Includes supplementary data on allied Cody & other lines by E.P. Cody.
    Includes letter written by Mr. Payne to Mr. Cody, November and December 1953.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as CS71.D322 1953a.
  - Genealogy of Colonel Thomas Dennis, his forebearers & descendants, 1908-1911; Compiled by Thomas Little; T003197
  - Brief of title, Colonel Thomas Dennis lands, Ipswich, Mass., 1660-1911, 1908-1911; Compiled by Thomas Little; T003197
  - Family record: Denslow - McKenzie / compiled by Helen Rebecca (Denslow) McKenzie, circa 1903; 1 volume; 2002-032
    Offered to Florence L. McKenzie Roberts, January 10, 1903, from her mother.
    Donated to the Connecticut State Library by George McKenzie Roberts in 1959.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 D433mc
    Related material may be found at [CSL call number StLib History Reference Spec.Gen.File MacKenzie]
- E
  - Genealogical notes on the Ellsworth family, undated; 1 volume; 2002-033
    Donated to the Connecticut State Library by the Ruth Wyllys Chapter, D.A.R. on July 7, 1942.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 EL59n
- F
  - Farnham family genealogical records, undated; 1999-178
    This item is shelved with the classified archives. Researchers should request this item using call number 929.2 F22b.
    Received April 1, 1913, from William F.J. Boardman.
  - Genealogy of the Francis family, 1894; 1 volume; 2002-044
    Copied from manusscript for William F. Boardman.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 F843b
- G
  - List of births, marriages and deaths under the name Gordon, Gaordon, Gordan, Gordien, Gordins, Gordton, Gorndon [see also Gorton] as found in the general index of Connecticut vital records Nov. 27, 1933; List of births, marriages and deaths under the name Gorden as found in the general index of Connecticut church records, Nov. 28, 1933, 1933, negative photostat; T003210
    "This alphabetical arrangement ... was made from the General Index of Connecticut Vital Records and covers entries found in the records of the Town Clerk's Offices from the formation of the towns to about 1850"--T.p. verso
  - Godard, Goddard, Gosard, Gossard, Gozard, Gozzard in general index of Connecticut vital records as of September 15, 1930, typescript + negative photostat; T003270
  - Notes on Griffin ancestry, undated; 1999-100
    Includes two portrait photographs.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 G875.
- H
  - Ancestral charts & notes on John Hall & descendants, together with Samuel Orcutt's family records, undated; 1 folder; 2002-034
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 H147.
  - Hallett
    See: Cornell.
  - Hanks family charts, 1930; 1 volume; 2002-035
    Donated to the Connecticut State Library by the Genealogical Society of Utah in 1930.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 H194g.
  - Hastings genealogical notes, undated; T003198
  - Hebard family genealogical collection, undated; 2 items; 2002-036
    See also: Genealogy of the Hibbard family who are descendants of Robert Hibbard of Salem, Massachusetts
    - Notes on the Hebard family, undated
      Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 H353n.
    - Genealogy of the Hebard family, undated
      Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 H353.
  - Genealogy of the Hibbard family who are descendants of Robert Hibbard of Salem, Massachusetts / compiled and published by Augustine George Hibbard, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1901; 1 volume, mimeograph; 2002-036
    Pages 8-55 of 1901 edition: Genealogy of the Hibbard family who are descendants of Robert Hibbard of Salem, Massachusetts
    Donated to the Connecticut State Library by Mrs. Charles Borman on February 8, 1952.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 H521h.
  - Higgins family data, 1633-1813 / copied by Mary Estelle Benham from Higgins data lent by Stanley W. Smith of Boston, 1917; 1 volume; 2002-045
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 H434be.
  - Unpublished records in the line of Richard Higgins and his descendants / compiled by M. Estelle Benham, circa 1931; 11 leaves, photostat; 2002-037
    Donated to the Connecticut State Library by Mrs. Benham on March 27, 1931.
    This photostatic copy was made by M. Estelle Benham, from the original copy compiled from data furnished her by Eugene Higgins, Jackson, Michigan.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 H534b.
  - Hinckley genealogical notes, memoranda and charts, undated; T003199
- J
  - Jewett family genealogy / Compiled by M. J. Stark, North Lyme, Connecticut; With index, circa 1936; T003220; negative photostat
  - Note book of George Ransom Johnson, Copper Valley, Cheshire, Connecticut, 1877-1907; with Johnson family records, 1746-1934, 1 volume, negative photostat; 2002-070
    Contents: Copper Valley, History of; Copper Valley picnics; Hitchcock block account, 1906-1908; Johnson Family; Johnson, George Ransom; Johnson, Miss Nettie E account at the block, 1904-1908; Johnson, Robert James, children; Miscellaneous notes and records of deaths; Norton Family records.
    Photostat copy made at Connecticut State Library from original volume loaned for the purpose on November 1, 1938 by Mr. Robert Johnson, Cheshire.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 fJ625.
- K
  - Ancestors of Edith Margaret Kelley b. June 30, 1896 and Augustus Sawyer Kelley b. December 12, 1896, of Millbridge, Maine, son and daughter of Ira Jones (1866-1937) and Sara S. (Wallace) Kelley (1873-1957) / compiled by Edith Margaret (Kelley) Ashe Colton, 1968; 1999-102; 3 volumes
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 K287c.
- L
  - Lothrop-Lathrop-Lowthroppe genealogical notes, undated; T003200
    Related material may be found at [CSL call number History Reference Spec.Gen.File Lothrop]
  - Jean de Luce / by Ellen Coit Elliot, 1957; 3 leaves (2 copies); 1993-045
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 920 L96291e.
  - Genealogical notes on the ancestry of John Chester Lyman, 1944; 1999-101; 1 volume
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 L989Lym.
    Related material may be found at [CSL call number StLib History Reference Spec.Gen.File Lyman]
- M
  - Marsh genealogical notes and coat of arms, undated; T003201
    Related material may be found at [CSL call number History Reference Spec.Gen.File Marsh]
  - McKenzie
    See: "Family record: Denslow - McKenzie: listed under Denslow.
  - Dr. Norman Morrison genealogical notes, undated; T003202
- N
  - Ancestry of Ferdinand Favor Norris, 1872-1910, Hartford, Conn., 1914; T003203
  - Norton genealogical notes, 1911-1913; T003204
- O
  - Orcutt
    See: "Ancestral charts & notes on John Hall & descendants, together with Samuel Orcutt's family records" listed under Hall.
  - A genealogical record of Benjamin Oviatt: who emigrated from Goshen, Litchfield County, Connecticut to Hudson, Summit County, Ohio in 1801 and his descendants / compiled by Frank Coriell Oviatt, South Euclid, Ohio, 1934, T003211; negative photostat
- P
  - Genealogical data, Patten and allied families / collected by Ella Louise Patten, undated; 1 volume; 2002-046
    Contents: Ella Louise Patten (photo); E. Louise Patten obituary; Patten family; Davis family; Pomeroy family; Holmes family; Cooke family; Washburn family; Torrey family; Torrey family (English); Burt family; Longmeadow: Lay-out of central street from Srpingfield to Enfield; Stebbins family; Colton family; Bliss family; Chapin family; Hale line; Miscellaneous papers.
    Donated by Mrs. William Haine (Norma Allen) of West Hartford through her aunt, Mrs. William Allen, Winsted, June 19, 1950.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 P277p.
  - Historical statement...written for a family celebration in 1876 / by Newman Peck, 1 volume, negative photostat; 2002-071
    Newman Peck was born in 1795, son of Lament5 (Zebulon4, Samuel3, Saumuel2, Deacon Paul1 of Hartford). Zebulon, Lament, and Newman resided in Bristol; Newman removed to Wisconsin in 1841.
    This statement includes some details about the family which do not appear in the section on Deacon Paul Peck in Ira B. Peck's "Genealogical History..." (1868), pages 367-389 #5, 24, 55, 131-139, 319-130, 605-612. Pages 18-365 of the statement is reminiscences of Peck's early days in Bristol, under the following headings: Schools, Churches, Amusements, Military, Temperance, Clocks, Whipping Post, Whigs and Tories, Witchcraft, Wagons, Physicians, Attorneys, Mineral, and Manufacturing.
    Photostat copy from original manuscript owned by Miss Ellen Barnard Peck, of Bristol, loaned to the Connecticut State Library for photostating October 10, 1950 via Justice Newell Jennings.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 920 P336.
  - Corrections and additions gathered before 1951 by Celese Pember Hazen to The Pember Family, published 1939, undated; 1 volume; 2002-047
    See also: John Pember,: the history of the Pember family in America
    Received from C.P. Hazen, November 30, 1951.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 P37h supp.
- R
  - Rathbone genealogy / by John C. Cooley; A complete history of the Rathbone family, dating from 1574 to date, 1898; T003212; negative photostat
    The item in RG074 is the index only.
  - Remington and allied families records / Compiled by Miss Grace Clark, Marblehead, Massachusetts, circa 1932; T003221; negative photostat
  - Robbins family Bible records, 1823-1915; 2005-039
    Robbins lived on Mill Creek Road, Old Lyme, in the ninteenth century.
    Donated by Cynthia Kovak, January 27, 2005.
  - The Rogers family, circa 1904; T003213; negative photostat
  - Akron as known by Russells occupying Newstead / by L.B. Russell, Comanche, Texas, 1934; 1 scrapbook; 2002-038
    Series of articles on the Russell family clipped from the Akron news, and other Russell items.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 R912rus.
- S
  - Record of our great grandfather's family, Thomas Selden / compiled by Hattie S. Selden, undated; 1 notebook; 2002-039
    Copied from the family record.
    Additional data to that published in: Selden ancestry, a family history
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 Se43r s.
  - Seymour family genealogical data, 1975; 1 volume, negative photostat; 2002-040
    "Photostat copy made from original loaned by Mrs. Dorothy Seymour Byrnes, 42 Sherman St., Hartford, Conn., on Aug. 15, 1935."
    Includes photostat copies of historical reminiscences of the Congregational church in Stillwater, by Rev. Lebbeus Armstrong.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 fSe95r se.
  - Seymour genealogical notes, undated; T003205
  - Seymour genealogical notes and Revolutionary service / compiled by Jennie E. (Seymour) Hammond of West Hartford, undated; 1 volume; 2002-048
    Received from Mrs. Hammond's estate, May 16, 1946.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 Se95h.
  - Charles Lyman Shaw genealogical notebooks, circa 1890-1900; 13 items; 2011-025
    Charles Lyman Shaw was born February 7, 1842 in Plainfield, Mass. and died May 27, 1902 in Astoria, Long Island, N.Y.
    Notebooks are numbered 1-8, 10-12, 14. There is one notebook with a missing front cover and thus unnumbered.
    The at the University of Massachusetts Amherst contains one folder of Charles Lyman Shaw's writings, circa 1894.
  - Skinner genealogical notes and chart, undated; T003206
  - Ancestral lines of Belle Elizabeth Slate (Hinckley), undated; T003222
  - Family lines / Mabel (Smith) Askue, circa 1925; T003216; negative photostat
  - Stow family in America - Milford, Conn. branch, undated; 1 notebook; 2002-041
    Possibly from the collection of Rollin U. Tyler of Haddam, Conn.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 St78 s.
  - Sturgis genealogical notes, memoranda, coat-of-arms, 1898, undated; T003207
- T
  - Thorne
  - Trumbull genealogical notes, undated; T003208
- V
  - Vaughn genealogical record / compiled by Annie E. Vaughn (b. 1806) of Norwich, undated; 1 volume; 2002-096
    Vaughns of Rhode Island and Norwich, Conn. with notes and working papers attached.
    Purchased from Miss Helen E. Royce, Hartford, January 18, 1955.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 V465v.
- W
  - List of births, marriages and deaths under the name Walch: as found in the General Index of Connecticut Vital Records April 30, 1934, T003214; negative photostat
  - Descendants of John Warner (Suffield, Conn., about 1690) and Elizabeth (Mighel) Warner / [compiled by R. Miles Warner and Charles R. Hale], circa 1935; T003215; negative photostat
  - White family. Decendants of James2 of Hebron, Conn. (son of James1 with lists of heirs and their addresses, 1952; 1 notebook; 2002-049
    Gift of Mrs. Carles Borman, West Hartford, February 8, 1952.
    Transferred to Archives from general collection. Formerly catalogued as 929.2 W5826w j.
  - Woodruff genealogical notes, undated; T003209